Hey. Hello.
Jim!
What's up, buddy? This is not
funny. Why is my stuff in here?
That's weird. A dollar for a
stapler, that's pretty good.
Yeah, well, I'm not paying
for my own stuff, okay?
I know you did this, 'cause you're
friends with the vending machine guy.
Who, Steve? Yeah, Steve.
Whatever his name is. What
do I want? What do I want?
It's a pencil cup.
Oh, no, no, no. That's my pencil
cup. I don't think so, I just bought it.
I think so, and you're
gonna hand it over to me.
I love these.
Okay, fine.
Where's my wallet?
There it is. J1.
Here, you know what?
I don't have any...
I've got some nickels.
$0.05, $0.10,
$0.15, $0.20, $0.25...
Hello, everyone.
Good morning, Michael.
Where are we
going this afternoon?
Last week, Michael sent
out this mysterious memo.
"It's time for our first-quarter
camaraderie event."
"So pack a swimsuit, a toothbrush,
rubber-soled shoes and a ski mask."
A ski mask and a swimsuit.
So that he can have us rob a bank
and then escape through the sewers.
And brush our teeth.
Yeah.
Michael. Stanley, bo-banley.
I need to know...
Banana-fana-fo-fanley.
What we're doing.
Me, my, mo, manly.
You said bring a
toothbrush. Stanley.
Is this an overnight? Maybe.
The suspense is just
so exciting, isn't it?
Should my wife tell her boss
she's not coming in tomorrow?
Maybe. I don't know.
Not maybe. Yes or no?
Well, no, but... Okay, don't
spoil it for everybody, all right?
But we are going on a booze
cruise on Lake Wallenpaupack.
In January?
It's cheaper.
This is not just another party.
This is a leadership
training exercise.
Right?
I'm going to combine elements of
fun and motivation and education
into a single
mind-blowing experience.
It is now time to unveil
the destination of
this year's retreat.
We are going on a harbor
cruise of Lake Wallenpaupack.
Yes!
It's a booze cruise. All right!
I have a test for business
school tomorrow night.
Is it okay if I skip the
cruise and study for that?
No, this is mandatory.
But don't worry. You know
what? You're gonna learn plenty.
This is gonna turn
your life around, Ryan.
I'm already in business
school. Well, this...
Wait, Michael. Yeah?
Why did you tell us to bring a
bathing suit? To throw you off the scent.
Yeah, but I bought
a bathing suit.
Well, just keep the tags
on and you can return it.
I took the tags off already. Well,
that's not my fault, okay? Just...
We're not gonna
pay for a bathing suit.
Okay, I know what you're all thinking.
"Who is this smart little cookie?"
Her name is Brenda something,
and she is from Corporate.
And she is here, like you, to
learn from what I have to say.
I am a great
motivational speaker.
I attended a Tony Robbins
event by the airport last year and...
It wasn't the actual course. You
have to pay for the actual course.
But it talked about
the actual course.
And I've incorporated a lot of
his ideas into my own course.
Leader... ship.
The word "ship" is hidden
inside the word "leadership"
as its derivation.
So if this office
is in fact a ship,
as its leader,
I am the captain.
But we're all in the
same boat. Teamwork!
Last year, Michael's theme
was "Bowl over the competition."
So guess where we went.
Now, on this ship
that is the office,
what is the sales department?
Anyone?
How about the sales
department is the sails?
Yes, Darryl, the sales
department makes sales. Good.
Let me just explain. I see the
sales department as the furnace.
A furnace? How old is this ship?
How about the anchor? PHYLLIS:
What does the furnace do?
All right, let's not get hung
up on the furnace. It's just...
It's the sales... I see the sales
department are down there.
They're in the engine room, and
they're shoveling coal into the furnace.
Right?
I mean, who saw
the movie Titanic?
They were very important
in the movie Titanic.
Who saw it? Show of hands.
Not really sure what
movie you're talking about.
Are you sure you got
the title right? Titanic.
I think you're thinking of
The Hunt for Red October.
No! I'm... Leo
DiCaprio! Come on!
Michael stands in
the front of the boat
and says that he's king of
the world within the first hour,
or I give you my next paycheck.
Michael, everyone in
the engine room drowned.
No. Thank you, spoiler alert.
You saw the movie,
those of you who did. You...
They're happy down
there in the furnace room.
And they're dirty
and grimy and sweaty.
And they're singing
their ethnic songs and...
Actually, that might
be warehouse.
What? The... No,
no... No, I didn't...
Okay. Well, the... Okay, in a
nutshell, what I'm saying is "leadership."
We'll talk more about
that on the boat. Ship.
Aye-aye, Captain.
A three hour tour
Pam, you are Mary Ann.
We have the
Professor and Ginger.
Welcome aboard!
Angela, you are
Mrs. Howell, Lovey.
The native. Sometimes
they come from neighboring...
We have one of
the Globetrotters.
I am the Skipper, and,
Dwight, you will be Gilligan!
Cool!
Actually, I'm the skipper. Okay.
But you could be
Gilligan. No! I'd rather die.
Hi. I am Michael Scott. I
am the captain of this party.
I'm Captain Jack.
I'm captain of the ship.
I'm also captain of anyone
who sets foot on this ship.
Hi, welcome aboard. Okay.
In an office, when
you are ranking people,
manager is higher than captain.
On a boat, who
knows? It's nebulous.
Hey, look! I'm
king of the world!
Okay, all right!
Welcome aboard!
I am your captain, Captain Jack.
And I am the Regional Manager
of Dunder Mifflin, Michael Scott.
Welcome, welcome!
Okay, so... Okay, so...
Please. The life
preservers... Right.
They are located underneath the
seats all along the perimeter of the boat.
Don't worry, you are not gonna
be needing life preservers tonight.
Well, we might be.
It's just gonna be...
Please let me finish.
Okay? Thank you. Well...
So the Coast Guard requires that I
tell you where the safety exits are.
Now, on this ship, it's very
easy. Anywhere over the side.
Not only am I your ship's captain,
I am also your party captain!
We're gonna get it going
here in just a few minutes.
And I'm your party captain, too!
And you are gonna put on
your dancing shoes later on!
Hey, Mike, Mike, Mike.
So we are gonna...
If you don't mind... rock it!
What? Please! Okay?
If the boat's rocking,
don't come knocking!
Michael. Yeah?
Your company employees are not the
only people on the boat tonight. Okay?
We're all gonna have a good
time tonight. Hey, listen, listen, Mike.
Why don't you let me
and my crew do our job?
You just sit back and have
a good time. Okay. Yep. So...
All right?
You guys, it's like we're in high
school and we're at the cool table.
Right? Yeah.
Pam, were you a cheerleader?
No, she was total "Miss
Arts y-Farts y" in high school.
She wore the turtleneck and
everything. That's hilarious.
It's not hilarious...
Where did you go to school?
Bishop O'Hare.
His-slop-who-cares-a...?
We played you!
You really look
familiar. Did you...
You cheered for
them, didn't you?
No. Yes, I did.
A-W-E-S-O-M-E
Awesome, awesome is what we
are We're the football superstars!
A-W-E-S-O-M-E
I remember that, and we
crushed you, like, 42-10.
Having fun? Yeah.
Everybody's really nice.
Good, well, that is what
Scranton is all about.
Not like you New Yorkers! So...
When are you gonna
start the presentation?
I already sort of started
it back at the office
and on the dock
with the Gilligan thing.
So, right now, I was thinking.
Yes, okay!
Listen up, all you
Dunder Mifflinites!
I would like to talk to you
all about life preservers.
Now, one important life
preserver in business is IT support.
Not now, Mike,
we're doing the limbo!
That's right, partiers, it's
time to limbo, limbo, limbo!
So, okay.
All right, I need a volunteer to
come up here and hold my stick!
Who's it gonna be?
Okay. Me, me, me.
Usually it's a
woman. I'm stronger.
Hey, I got an idea.
How would you like to
steer the ship, Dwight?
Keep us on a steady course. Keep
a sharp eye out. I'm counting on you.
I was the youngest pilot in
Pan Am history. When I was four,
the pilot let me ride in the
cockpit and fly the plane with him.
And I was four and I was great.
And I would have landed it, but my
dad wanted us to go back to our seats.
All right, all right,
that was great!
Now it's time for
the dance contest!
Why don't we do that
after I do my presentation?
Nope. Dance contest!
All right, we'll have a
motivational dance contest!
Hit it!
Yeah! Okay! Dancing!
It is a primal art form
used in ancient times
to express yourself
with the body!
And communicate!
Sometimes you
have to take a break
from being the kind of boss that's
always trying to teach people things.
Sometimes you have to
just be the boss dancing.
What do you do
with a drunken sailor?
with a drunken sailor
Early in the morning?
Come inside and
talk to me. I can't.
Do you want us to
run aground, woman?
Snorkel shot! Snorkel shot!
Snorkel shot! Snorkel
shot! Snorkel shot!
Yeah!
Who's next? Come on!
Pammy, come on! Come
on! No, I'm not doing that.
Come on!
Hey, why don't we find, like,
a quieter place to hang out?
No, I just gotta wait for Darryl
to do his shot. Just a minute.
Come on. Darryl! Darryl!
It's getting kind of
rowdy down there. Yeah.
"Darryl, Darryl, Darryl!"
Sometimes I just don't get Roy.
I mean, I don't know.
So...
What's it like dating
a cheerleader?
I'm cold.
So, what's this
presentation all about?
See? This is of
general interest.
It is about priorities
and making decisions,
using the boat as an analogy.
What is important to you?
If the boat is sinking,
what do you save?
Women and children. No,
no, salesmen and profit centers.
That's a stupid analogy. Okay.
Well, obviously you don't
know anything about leadership.
Well, I was the captain of a
PC-1 Cyclone coastal patrol boat
during Desert Storm.
Wow, you should be
the motivational speaker.
Him? Okay.
Yeah, he gives me real
responsibility, Michael.
Captain Jack delegates.
He's let me steer the
ship for the last hour.
I'd like to be engaged.
How did you manage
to pull that off?
I've been engaged for three
years, and there's no end in sight.
So you don't want
to ask my advice.
Suppose your office
building's on fire,
Jim, who would you save?
Let's see...
The customer, because
the customer is king.
Not what I was looking
for, but a good thought.
He's just sucking up.
When you were in the Navy,
did you ever almost die?
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah, and I wasn't
thinking about some customer.
I was thinking
about my first wife.
The day I got back
on shore, I married her.
You know what? I would
save the receptionist.
I just wanted to clear that up.
Everybody,
could I get your attention
for just a second?
Can you listen to
me for a second?
We were up at the
front, and we were
talking about what's
really important and...
Pam,
I think enough is enough.
I think we should set
a date for our wedding.
How about June 10th?
Come on, let's do it!
Come on, baby!
Yeah! Congratulations!
Congratulations!
Yeah! Yeah!
Oh, my God! I love you, baby!
Congratulations!
You know what, I don't
want to take credit for this,
but Roy and I were just
having a conversation
about making commitments
and making choices. Right?
Did I motivate you?
No, it's Captain Jack.
Well... Captain Jack.
Could have been
either one of us,
because we pretty much
were saying the same thing.
Congratulations! That is great!
- We gotta celebrate!
- Yeah!
Hey, hey, hey! I got
an idea, I got an idea.
I could marry you right
now as captain of the ship.
Yes!
I could marry you as Regional
Manager of Dunder Mifflin!
No, no, no. I want my
mom and dad to be there.
Then I'll give you away!
No, thank you.
Do you think that'll
ever be us? No.
What is wrong with you? Why
did you even bring me here tonight?
I don't know.
Let's break up. What?
This is where old Captain
Jack drives the boat.
Wow!
Seasick?
Captain Jack says you
should look at the moon.
Captain Jack's a fart-face.
I'm on medication. Really? What?
Vomacillin.
Okay, all right.
It's time to be boss.
Time to motivate. Let's
blow some minds here.
Okay, guys, guys, guys. Cool it.
Everybody? Dunder
Mifflin Scranton employees,
Brenda, I've some very, very
urgent news I need to tell everybody.
Right now. Listen up.
The ship is sinking.
Okay?
We're going down right now.
Just wrap your heads
around the reality of that.
Please! Everybody,
it's my turn now, okay?
Captain Jack is gone.
In five minutes, this ship is going
to be at the bottom of the lake,
and there aren't enough
spaces on the lifeboat.
Who are we gonna save?
Do we save sales?
Do we save customer service?
Do we save accounting?
This is a business
scenario. Right?
It's a scary... It's a predicament.
Hey! What the hell is going on here?
And it's something that each and
every one of us have to think about.
I'm in the brig. See?
The boat's not as
corporate-friendly as advertised.
What is the deal with the guy
jumping overboard? What was...
If he had just waited and
heard what I had to say,
he would be motivated
right now, and not all wet.
Is somebody there?
What happened to you?
Captain Jack has a
problem with authority.
Right, 'cause you announced
that his ship was sinking?
Yeah. He just totally lost it.
If you ask me, he
caused the panic.
What a night.
Well, it's nice for you.
Your friend got engaged.
She was always engaged. Roy
said the first one didn't count.
That's great.
You know, to tell you the truth,
I used to have a big
thing for Pam. So...
Really? You're kidding me.
You and Pam? Wow!
I would have never put you two
together. You really hid it well. God!
I usually have a
radar for stuff like that.
You know I made out
with Jan. Yeah, I know.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, Pam is cute. Yeah.
She's really funny,
and she's warm,
and she's just...
Anyway. Well, if
you like her so much,
don't give up.
She's engaged. BFD.
Engaged ain't married.
Never, ever, ever give up.
Don't worry, Michael.
I'm taking us to shore.
It's a fake wheel, dummy.